DALEK: Who are you?
你是谁
DELAK: Who are you?
DELAK: Answer!
回答
- DOCTOR: Why are you being so cautious?
- JAMIE: Ssh!
- 你为什么这么谨慎  - 嘘
JAMIE: They left the door open for us, didn't they?
他们给我们留门了，对不
- JAMIE: It's half past the nine o'clock.
- DOCTOR: Yes, I know.
- 这才9点半呢  - 是的，我知道
JAMIE: They made the appointment for ten.  Why have we come early?
他们约的时间是10点，我们这么早来干什么？
DOCTOR: The early bird catches the worm, Jamie.
Do be quiet, there's a good chap.
早起的鸟儿有虫吃，Jamie。别出声，好小伙
DOCTOR: And don't knock into anything.
还有别撞上任何东西
DOCTOR: Ssh!
嘘！
JAMIE: Any good, this?
有什么发现吗
DOCTOR: It's interesting.
这很有意思
DOCTOR: In fact, Jamie, it's quite remarkable.
事实上，Jamie，这很令人吃惊
JAMIE: You told me outside it said "Genuine Victorian Antiques".
在外面时你说这是“维多利亚真品古董”
JAMIE: All the stuff in here is brand new!
这里所有的东西都是新的！
- DOCTOR: You noticed that.
- JAMIE: Of course I did. The man's a rogue.
- 你注意到啦  - 那当然。这人是个大盗
DOCTOR: Yes, so it seems.
是的，看来很像
- DOCTOR: Except...
- JAMIE: Except what?
- 除非。。。  - 除非什么？
DOCTOR: Except that all these things are not reproductions.
They're all genuine.
除非这些都不是新生产的，它们都是真品
- JAMIE: That's ridiculous!
- DOCTOR: Look at this.
- 这不可能！- 你看看这个
DOCTOR: "To one deed box, four guineas. "
支出四基尼，契税箱
DOCTOR: This is a bill from William Deering and Son. 1866.
这是一张记账单，属于 William Deering and Son，1866年
JAMIE: Then it's a forgery.
那它就是伪造的
DOCTOR: If you were going to make a forgery, wouldn't you dirty it up a bit?
如果你要伪造一个东西, 你不会来点做旧什么的？
DOCTOR: Yellow the edges, crinkle it up? This is brand-new.
把边缘搞成黄色，把它弄皱一点？这张是新的
- JAMIE: I've got an idea.   - DOCTOR: What?
- 我有个想法 - 什么
- JAMIE: All the stuff in here is genuine...   - DOCTOR: Yes.
- 这里所有东西都是真的。。。 - 是吗
- JAMIE: .. but brand-new. - DOCTOR: Well done.
- 但都是新的 - 猜得不错
JAMIE: That is impossible, unless Waterfield could have invented a time machine,
但这是不可能的，除非 Waterfield 建造了一架时间机器
JAMIE: and he's bringing this stuff back from Victorian times.
然后他从维多利亚时期带回了这东西
DOCTOR: It's not very likely, but the only way
to find out is to ask Waterfield.
这不太可能，不过搞明白的唯一办法是问问这位 Waterfield
WATERFIELD: Kennedy!
WATERFIELD: What happened?
什么情况？
DELAK: The human discovered our communication system.
这个人发现了我们的通讯系统
- WATERFIELD: And you murdered him?
- DELAK: He would have betrayed us.
- 然后你就杀了他？  - 他很可能出卖我们
- WATERFIELD: You don't have to kill!
- DELAK: Silence!
- 你没必要要他的命啊！ - 收声！
WATERFIELD: What are you dragging me into? You took a human life.
Don't you understand that?
你都把我拖到什么事里面了啊？你夺走了一个人的生命，你明白吗？
- DELAK: That is of no consequence.
- WATERFIELD: No consequence?
- 这并没有什么后果 - 没有后果？
DELAK: There is only one form of life that matters.
唯一需要在乎的就只有一种生命形式
DELAK: Dalek life.
Dalek 的生命
DELAK: Obey your orders, Waterfield!
服从命令，Waterfield！
WATERFIELD: No, wait! What am I to do with the body?
不，等等！我拿这尸体怎么办？
WATERFIELD: I can't...
我总不能。。。
WATERFIELD: I can't go on with this.
我没法干下去了
DOCTOR: I'm sure I heard somebody shouting.
我肯定听到了一点什么
- DOCTOR: We've got to get in.
- JAMIE: Use the wire.
- 我们得进去 - 用这个试试
DOCTOR: It's too pliable.
这太软了
PERRY: Oh! What are you doing here?
噢，你们在这里干什么？
- DOCTOR: You made the appointment!
- PERRY: For ten o'clock.
- 你约我们来的啊   - 说的是10点
DOCTOR: We thought we'd be early. What are you doing here?
我觉得应该早点来。你在这里干什么？
- PERRY: I work here.
- JAMIE: Then what are you creeping about for?
- 我在这里工作啊  - 那你怎么鬼鬼祟祟的？
DOCTOR: I think you've got some explaining to do, Mr Kenneth Perry!
我觉得有些事情你得解释一下，Kenneth Perry先生！
PERRY: My name isn't Kenneth. It's Keith. Look, I don't understand this.
我的名字不是 Kenneth，而是 Keith！不过，我没搞懂
DOCTOR: It's Keith... Do you know a man called Bob Hall?
是 Keith ？那你认识一个叫做 Bob Hall 的人吗？
PERRY: He's a man Mr Waterfield employs.
他是 Waterfield 先生雇佣的一个人
DOCTOR: He keeps some very rough company, including a man called Ken.
他有些不怎么样的同伙，其中有一个叫做 Ken
PERRY: Ken? Kennedy!
Ken？是 Kennedy 吧
- DOCTOR: What? What do you know about Kennedy?
- PERRY: Wait a minute. This is all too quick.
- 关于 Kennedy 你都知道些什么？ - 等一下，咱们别这么快
PERRY: I'll answer your questions if you'll answer mine.
如果你先回答我的问题，我就回答你们的
PERRY: This old police box was for a collector of curios.
这个警察亭是给一个收藏家准备的
- DOCTOR: But it belongs to me!
- PERRY: Why is it so important to you?
- 但它是我的！ - 为什么它对你这么重要？
DOCTOR: Because... because of what's inside it,
and because it happens to be my property.
因为它里面的东西，因为它碰巧是我的财产
- DOCTOR: Where is it?
- PERRY: At the back.
- 它在哪儿？     - 就在后面
- DOCTOR: Is there another way through, this door is locked.
- PERRY: We might be able to get over the yard gates.
- 那还有别的路过去吗？这个门锁住了 - 我们得先穿过院门
- PERRY: This door has an electric lock on it.
- DOCTOR: You're going to show me where this yard is.
- 那门上有一个电子锁  - 你要给我们说一下院子在哪儿
PERRY: I see. But If it's a police box, shouldn't we get the police?
我明白了。不过如果这是一个警察亭，我们是不是应该叫警察来？
JAMIE: Doctor!
博士！
PERRY: That's Kennedy!
这是 Kennedy！
DOCTOR: He's dead.
他死了
- DOCTOR: What are you doing?
- PERRY: Getting the police.
- 你要干什么？        - 叫警察
PERRY: Don't touch anything. I'll be as quick as I can.
别碰任何东西, 我尽量快点
- JAMIE: Should we have let him go?
- DOCTOR: He's right.
- 我们应该让他走吗？      - 他做得没错
- JAMIE: But the Tardis!
- DOCTOR: We'll have to find it before he comes back.
- 但是 TARDIS 呢？  - 我们必须在他回来之前找到它
DOCTOR: I wonder what this telephone interference is.
我很好奇这电话干扰是怎么回事
- JAMIE: Looks as if Waterfield's cleared out.
- DOCTOR: Why make an appointment to see us at ten?
- 看起来 Waterfield 早跑掉了 - 他为什么要约我们在10点见面呢？
JAMIE: Obviousely he didn't know he was going to have a fight
with Kennedy. Let's find the Tardis and go!
他并不知道他要跟Kennedy 搏斗一场。我们还是找到TARDIS 离开吧
DOCTOR: Yes, the Tardis...
是的，找TARDIS
DOCTOR: How did he die?
他是怎么死的
DOCTOR: His limbs are stiff, his hands clenched..
他四肢僵硬，双手紧握
DOCTOR: He died in horrible agony. Look at his face.
他死的时候肯定很的痛苦，看他的脸
- DOCTOR: Hello...
- JAMIE: What?
- 看看        - 什么？
- JAMIE: It's your picture!
- DOCTOR: Yes.
- 是你的照片           - 是的
DOCTOR: Now, he fell like that, with his arm stretched out.
看，他的姿势好像是要去够什么东西
DOCTOR: Jamie，go out into the hall,
and measure the length of it up to the door here.
Jamie, 你走到大厅去。量一下那里到这个门的距离
- JAMIE: 14... 15.
- DOCTOR: It's only five from the door to the wall.
- 14。。。15   - 从门到墙这里只有5步
DOCTOR: There must be another room behind here.
这后面肯定还有一个房间
JAMIE: Hey, Doctor! There's a keyhole.
嘿，博士！这里有个锁孔
DOCTOR: You're right. Waterfield will have the key.
你说得对，Waterfield 应该有钥匙
DOCTOR: We'd better find something to prise it open with.
我们最后找个什么东西把它翘开
DOCTOR: Well...
好了。。。
DOCTOR: Look at this.
看看这个
DOCTOR: That's where your telephone interference is coming from.
电话干扰就是从这里来的
DOCTOR: This is interesting.
这很有意思
- JAMIE: Hey! The other half of your picture!
- DOCTOR: Don't open that!
- 嘿！你照片的另一半！   - 别打开那个！
PERRY: This way. Along here.
这边，在这里
PERRY: Here we are.
我们到了
That's funny... There were a couple of other gentlemen here.
奇怪。。。刚才这里还有两个人呢
PERRY: They seem to have... disappeared.
他们好像已经。。。消失了
MOLLIE: Hello, sir.
你好，先生
MOLLIE: Are you feeling better?
你感觉好点了吗
MOLLIE: Oh, you did have a party last night, didn't you, sir!
哦，你昨晚肯定参加聚会了，对不
- MOLLIE: The master sent this in for you.
- DOCTOR: The master?
- 主人要我把这个送进来   - 主人？
- DOCTOR: Mr Waterfield?
- MOLLIE: No, sir. Mr Maxtible.
- Waterfield 先生吗？  - 不，先生。是 Maxtible 先生
MOLLIE: Mr Waterfield came back from abroad last night, sir,
with you and the young gentleman.
Waterfield 先生才回来，先生，跟你和那位年轻绅士一起的啊
- MOLLIE: Don't you remember?
- DOCTOR: Not very well, no.
- 你不记得了吗？ - 记不太清了
MOLLIE: Ooh!
噢！
MOLLIE: I'd best not wake him.
我没有吵醒他吧
- DOCTOR: What's your name?
- MOLLIE: Mollie Dawson, sir.
- 你叫什么名字   - 我叫 Mollie Dawson, 先生
- DOCTOR: This stuff works remarkably quickly.
- MOLLIE: Am I to pour some more?
- 这东西见效太快了  - 要我再倒一点吗
DOCTOR: No, thank you, Mollie, but you can tell me what the date is.
不了，谢谢你，Mollie。不过你可以跟我说说今天日期是什么
- MOLLIE: The date?
- DOCTOR: Yes.
- 日期？ - 是的
DOCTOR: I am feeling very much better,
我现在感觉好多了
DOCTOR: but I don't seem to be able to remember the date and where I am.
但我好像想不起来日期，也想不起来我在哪儿了
MAXTIBLE: Mollie, that will do.
Mollie, 这样就行了
MAXTIBLE: The answers you require, sir, might come better from me.
你想要的答案，先生，可能我能给出
MAXTIBLE: My name is Theodore Maxtible, and I am the owner of this house.
我的名字是 Theodore Maxtible，我是这个房子的主人
MAXTIBLE: Pray don't get up.
请不要起来
MAXTIBLE: I have the greatest sympathy for your condition
我对你的处境深表同情
MAXTIBLE: since I was the cause of it.
因为都是因我而起的
DOCTOR: And this is Mr Edward Waterfield, I presume.
而这位，我猜是 Edward Waterfield 先生
- DOCTOR: You don't keep appointments, do you?
- WATERFIELD: There were circumstances.
- 你没打算赴约，是不？ - 情况有点复杂
- DOCTOR: Yes, there were!
- MAXTIBLE: Please, Doctor. First things first.
- 是的，复杂！ - 博士，先说重要的事情吧
MAXTIBLE: You asked what date it was and where you were.
你在问你在何时何地
DOCTOR: Yes. Well?
嗯，你知道？
MAXTIBLE: You're in my house, some miles from Canterbury.
你在我的房子里，离坎特伯雷只有几里路
（注：坎特伯雷：英国英格兰东南部的市鎮, 离伦敦有几十公里）
MAXTIBLE: The date is June 2nd 1866.
当前日期是1866年6月2号
DOCTOR: What do you think you're up to? You steal my property,
你觉得你在干什么事？你偷了我的财产，
DOCTOR: spirit Jamie and me 100 years back in time
and murder a man along the way.
迷倒了 Jamie 和我, 把我们骗到了100年以前, 还顺道杀了一个人
WATERFIELD: We had nothing to do with the death of that man.
我们跟那个人的死没有关系
- DOCTOR: I don't believe you.
- MAXTIBLE: You will believe, Doctor.
- 我不相信你  - 你会相信的，博士
MAXTIBLE: All of us are victims of a higher power.
我们都是受害者，有一股强大的力量
MAXTIBLE: A power more evil and terrible than the human brain can imagine.
一股邪恶而可怕的力量，远超出人类所能想象
DOCTOR: Power? Victims? What do you mean?
力量？受害者？你什么意思？
- WATERFIELD: They've taken my daughter Victoria.
- DOCTOR: Who are they?
- 他们抓走了我女儿 Victoria  - 他们是谁？
MAXTIBLE: You will not be kept in suspense very much longer, Doctor.
你很快就会知道了，博士
MAXTIBLE: Pray come with us, and we will show you how it all began.
请跟我们来吧，我们跟你说明一下这一切是怎么开始的
WATERFIELD: Doctor, do whatever it is that they ask. I beg of you.
博士，不管他们要求你做什么，你都照做吧，我求你了
WATERFIELD: My daughter's life is in your hands.
我女儿的性命在你的手上
DOCTOR: I will listen. I promise.
我会仔细听，我保证
DOCTOR: Is er... Is that your daughter?
那个。。。那是你的女儿？
WATERFIELD: No, sir. That is a painting of my wife as a young girl.
不，先生，那画的是我的妻子，她年轻的时候
WATERFIELD: She is dead now, rest her soul, but Victoria is the image of her.
她已经去世了，愿她安息。不过 Victoria 长得很像她
DELAK: You have not eaten.
你还没有吃饭
DELAK: You will eat. That is an order. Answer!
你得吃，这是命令，回答我!
VICTORIA: Yes.
好
DELAK: You will not feed the flying pests outside.
你不得喂食外面的飞鸟
DELAK: Answer!
回答
VICTORIA: Yes.
好
DELAK: Move to the machine.
到机器那里去
DELAK: Move!
去
VICTORIA: No.
不
DELAK: Move!
走!
DELAK: The weight of your body has fallen by 17 ounces.
你的体重下降了17盎司
VICTORIA: What do you expect?
你还能指望怎么样？
VICTORIA: What do you expect? For pity's sake, let me go!
你还能指望怎么样？ 可怜可怜我, 放我走吧！
DELAK: Speak when you are told to speak!
让你说话的时候再说话
DELAK: More food will come.
还有更多食物会送过来
DELAK: Eat it, or you will be fed by force!
吃了它, 否则你会被强制喂食!
MAXTIBLE: Here we are, Doctor. This is hallowed ground.
我们走吧, 博士。这里地方比较神圣
MAXTIBLE: Here we shall not be disturbed by the servants.
在这里我们不会有仆人来打扰
DOCTOR: Yes, very impressive. Now perhaps you'll explain what all this is about?
嗯, 挺不错。现在你应该可以解释一下了吧, 这都是怎么回事？
MAXTIBLE: Patience, my dear sir.
稍安勿躁, 亲爱的先生
DOCTOR: Patience?! You don't seem to understand what's happened.
A man has been murdered!
稍安勿躁？你们好像还没搞懂发生了什么？都有个人被杀了！
DOCTOR: You behave as if we're going on a Sunday School outing.
你还弄得好像我们要去学校组织的周日郊游似的
MAXTIBLE: Neither Waterfield nor I were responsible for his death. Cigar?
他的死不是 Waterfield 的错, 也不是我的错。来根烟？
DOCTOR: Why have you brought us here?
你为什么带我们来这里？
DOCTOR: Who are these enemies of yours, these ones you say control you?
你们的敌人是谁？ 你说有人在控制你们？
- MAXTIBLE: Brilliant minds, Doctor.
- WATERFIELD: They are monsters!
- 高智商的头脑, 博士    - 他们都是怪物
- MAXTIBLE: Oh, I admit, Waterfield, they have behaved callously.
- WATERFIELD: Inhuman monsters!
- 哦, 我得承认, Waterfield, 他们做事情很冷血   - 不是人！
- DOCTOR: Inhuman?
- WATERFIELD: Creations of the devil!
- 不是人？  - 是邪恶的缔造者！
- MAXTIBLE: Let me explain.
- DOCTOR: Please do!
- 我来解释一下    - 赶紧的
MAXTIBLE: I've always been fascinated by the concept of travelling through time.
我一直都对时间旅行这个事情很着迷
MAXTIBLE: Waterfield here is an expert in certain technical matters,
这位 Waterfield 先生在技术方面是一位专家
MAXTIBLE: and I have the money to indulge my whims.
我也有点钱可以砸在自己的古怪想法上
MAXTIBLE: Everything you see about you was constructed by us two.
你在这里看到的所有东西都是我们俩建造的
- DOCTOR: To try to find a way of exploring time?
- MAXTIBLE: Yes.
- 为了找到穿越时间的方法？  - 是的
MAXTIBLE: Now, this is my theory.
好了, 现在说说我的理论
- MAXTIBLE: A mirror reflects an image, does it not?
- DOCTOR: Yes.
- 一面镜子可以反射图像, 对不？  - 可以
MAXTIBLE: So, you may be standing there
and yet appear to be standing 50 feet away.
所以, 你可以站在这里, 但又好像出现在50英尺之外
MAXTIBLE: Following the new investigations 12 years ago
by J Clark Maxwell into electromagnetism,
基于麦克斯韦在12年前在电磁场方面的研究
MAXTIBLE: and the experiments by Faraday into static electricity...
以及法拉第的静电实验。。。
- DOCTOR: Static?
- MAXTIBLE: Correct.
- 静电？    - 对
MAXTIBLE: .. Waterfield and I first attempted to define the image in the mirror,
。。Waterfield 和我试验了在镜子中固定图像
MAXTIBLE: and then to project it.
然后再投射出去
MAXTIBLE: In here, Doctor, are 144 separate mirrors.
这里, 博士, 有144面镜子
WATERFIELD: Each is of polished metal. Each is subjected to
electric charges, all positive.
每一面都是金属抛光制成的, 还会充上电, 一开始都是正电
MAXTIBLE: Like repels like in electricity, Doctor,
正如电负荷会同性相斥, 博士
MAXTIBLE: and so we attempted to repel the image in the mirrors wherever we directed.
于是我们尝试了在镜子间反射图像, 以让它到达我们期望的地方
- DOCTOR: You mentioned static electricity...
- WATERFIELD: That was our last experiment.
- 你刚才提到了静电。。。   - 那是我们最后的实验
（注: Daleks 的一个典型特征是采用静电作为个体能源, 博士在这里显然已经怀疑是Deleks在作怪了。Daleks首次出场01x02 The Daleks中第一任博士和Ian, Barbara他们就发现了Daleks采用静电作为能源。04x03 The Power of the Daleks中Daleks铺设静电传输地板以方便他们自己行动）
WATERFIELD: Negative and positive electricity had failed, so we tried static.
负电与正电都失败了, 所以我们尝试了静电
- WATERFIELD: If only we had know the powers we'd unleash.
- DOCTOR: Powers?
- 要是我早点知道就好了, 我们会放出什么样的力量   - 力量？
WATERFIELD: In the middle of our final test with static,
creatures burst out of the cabinet,
在我们最后一次静电实验中, 有种生物从柜子里面蹦出来了
WATERFIELD: invaded the house and took away my daughter.
入侵了我们的房子, 带走了我的女儿
MAXTIBLE: Oh, my dear fellow! My dear, dear fellow!
哦, 我亲爱的朋友, 可怜的家伙！
MAXTIBLE: We shall win through, now that the Doctor is here.
既然博士现在来了, 我们应该能赢了
WATERFIELD: These creatures... We had opened the way for them with our experiments.
这些生物。。。是我们的实验给他们打开了大门
WATERFIELD: They forced me into the horror of time travel.
他们强迫我进行时间旅行
WATERFIELD: They ordered me to steal a box belonging to you
他们命令我去偷你的那个箱子
WATERFIELD: and thus lure you into a trap and transport you here,
to get you with your colleague Mr McCrimmon.
以钓你上钩, 再把你们传输过来, 以抓住你和你的朋友 McCrimmon 先生
- DOCTOR: They knew about me?
- MAXTIBLE: They gave us likenesses.
- 他们认识我？    - 他们给了我们详细描述
WATERFIELD: What could I do? They said my daughter would die.
我能怎么办？ 他们说否则我的女儿就得死
- DOCTOR: What are they called, these creatures?
- DELAK: Doctor!
- 他们叫什么名字, 这些生物？  - 博士！
DELAK: Now do you understand?
现在你明白了吧？
DOCTOR: Oh, yes. Perfectly.
哦, 是的, 完全明白
DOCTOR: Move back!
退后！
DOCTOR: Our plan has worked.
我们的计划成功了
- DELAK: We shall triumph! You will obey!
- DOCTOR: Obey? What do you want?
- 我们会胜利！你将服从！  - 服从？你想要怎样？
DELAK: We have your time ship. We will destroy it
unless you help us with an experiment.
我们得到了你的时间飞船, 我们将销毁它, 除非你帮我们完成一向实验
DOCTOR: What experiment?
什么实验？
- DELAK: You will help us test another human being.
- DOCTOR: What sort of test?
- 你得帮我测试另外一个人类 - 测试什么？
- DELAK: No questions!
- DOCTOR: I won't be your slave!
- 不许问！   - 我可不会做你的奴隶！
- MAXTIBLE: Doctor, I beg you...
- DELAK: No harm will come to you if you agree.
- 博士, 求你了。。。。  - 如果你同意的话不会受到伤害的
DELAK: Where is your companion?
你的同伴在那里？
- DOCTOR: Jamie?
MAXTIBLE: He is in the house. - I have done everything you asked me to.
他在这所房子里。- 你让我干的事情, 我全都做了
- DOCTOR: Why do you ask about Jamie?
- DELAK: He is the human being who is to be tested.
- 你为什么问起 Jamie? - 他就是我们的实验对象
- DOCTOR: What do you mean? Tested how?
- DELAK: Silence! You will reveal nothing to your companion.
- 你什么意思？怎么实验？ - 安静! 你不得向你的同伴透露任何情况
DELAK: Obey the Daleks! You are in our power!
服从 Daleks 的命令! 你在我们的手上！
DOCTOR: What have you done with your infernal meddling?
你们到底插手干了些什么邪恶勾当？
DOCTOR: What is this test?
实验内容是什么？
- DOCTOR: Do either of you know?
- WATERFIELD: No.
- 你们俩知道吗？   - 不知道
MAXTIBLE: I believe I do.
我想我知道
MAXTIBLE: They, I mean the Daleks, tell me they've always been
defeated by human beings.
他们, 我是说这些 Daleks, 跟我说他们一直被人类打败
DOCTOR: In the long run, yes.
从长远来看, 是的
MAXTIBLE: Possibly because of some factor possessed by humans
可能是因为人类所具有的某些特质导致的
- DOCTOR: that is absent in Daleks?
- MAXTIBLE: Possibly.
- 而 Daleks 缺这些特质？ - 很可能
MAXTIBLE: Perhaps they want to find out what it is,
and transplant it into their race?
难道他们想搞明白到底是什么东西, 然后嫁接到他们这个种族上
WATERFIELD: But if they do do that, they ally this with their own
alien intelligence, they'll be invincible! Maxtible, you should have...
他们要是这样做了, 跟他们的外星智能联合起来, 他们就所向无敌了！ Maxtible, 你应该。。。
MAXTIBLE: My dear fellow, I am merely surmising. I know nothing definite.
亲爱的朋友, 我也只是猜测。我也不是太确定
MAXTIBLE: Besides, what could we have done, even if I had known for certain?
再说了, 就算我确实知道, 我又能做什么呢？
MAXTIBLE: The fact was, nay, is, they hold your daughter Victoria.
事实是, 他们关押了你的女儿 Victoria
DOCTOR: And now they've got Jamie.
现在他们又抓了 Jamie
MOLLIE: I'm sorry, sir. I didn't mean to wake you.
对不起, 先生, 我不是故意吵醒你的
JAMIE: It's not funny.
这不好笑
MOLLIE: The master left this for you to drink, sir.
主人把这个留给你喝的, 先生
MOLLIE: This'll clear away the cobwebs.
他可以让你清醒一点
- MOLLIE: Here you are, sir.
- JAMIE: Where's the Doctor?
- 给你, 先生   - 博士在哪儿？
- MOLLIE: He's with the master and Mr Waterfield.
- JAMIE: Waterfield?
- 他正跟主人和 Waterfield 先生在一起  - Waterfield？
- RUTH: What are you doing here?
- MOLLIE: Just seeing to the young gentleman, miss.
- 你在这里干什么？  - 刚过来看一下这位年轻的男士, 小姐
RUTH: Go and bring some tea.
去, 端点茶来
RUTH: Well, go along.
哎, 快去啊
- RUTH: Please, Mr McCrimmon.
- JAMIE: You know my name?
- 请坐, McCrimmon 先生   - 你知道我的名字？
RUTH: My father told me that you and your friend arrived last night, with Mr Waterfield.
我父亲告诉我说您和您的朋友昨晚到了, 跟 Waterfield 先生一起
JAMIE: Your father? I'm sorry I seem to have great difficulty in remembering anything.
您父亲？ 很抱歉, 我好像什么事情都很难想起来
RUTH: He owns this house. I'm his daughter, Ruth Maxtible.
这栋房子是他的。我是他的女儿, Ruth Maxtible
JAMIE: How do you do? Have you seen the Doctor this morning?
很高兴认识你。你今天早上见到博士了吗？
RUTH: He's talking with my father. He'll be along presently.
他跟我父亲在一起谈话, 很快就会过来
- RUTH: Do you have all you need?
- JAMIE: Whatever this stuff is, it works all right.
- 您还有什么需要的吗？  - 不知道这个东西是什么, 它很不错
- RUTH: Mollie shall bring you some tea.
- JAMIE: I'm obliged to you.
- Mollie 会给你端点茶过来的  - 我很感激
- JAMIE: Oh, Miss Maxtible.
- RUTH: Yes?
- Maxtible 小姐  - 什么?
- JAMIE: Could you tell me who that is in the portrait?
- RUTH: That's Mr Waterfield's late wife.
- 你能告诉我这张画里面是谁吗？   - 那是 Waterfield 已过世的妻子
- JAMIE: She is very lovely.
- RUTH: Yes, and his daughter looks just like her.
- 她很漂亮  - 是的, 她女儿跟她长得很像
- RUTH: You're quite comfortable?
- JAMIE: Yes, thank you.
- 请自便   - 好的, 谢谢你
JAMIE: 1866.
JAMIE: So that's what Waterfield's done.
原来这就是 Waterfield 干的好事
MOLLIE: Here we are, sir. I've been as quick as I could.
来了, 先生。我尽可能快了
MOLLIE: Shall I pour for you?
要我给你倒吗？
MOLLIE: Poor young gentleman. They shouldn't have given you so much to drink.
可怜的年轻人, 他们不应该让你喝那么多酒的
- WATERFIELD: Doctor... I do ask you to consider.
- DOCTOR: I have made up my mind.
- 博士。。。我真的请求你再考虑一下  - 我已经决定了
WATERFIELD: But they ordered you not to tell your friend anything.
但他们命令你不要告诉你朋友任何事
DOCTOR: Do you think I will allow Jamie to run into danger? No, I will not.
你觉得我会让 Jamie 陷入危险吗？不, 我不会的
- WATERFIELD: Suppose he refuses to do what they want?
- DOCTOR: We shall see.
- 假设他拒绝干呢？  - 看情况吧
DOCTOR: He's still asleep.
他还在睡觉
DOCTOR: The gas in that box of yours was pretty potent.
你那盒子里面的气体效果很强啊
WATERFIELD: It was Maxtible's invention.
那是 Maxtible 的发明
- DOCTOR: Jamie...
- WATERFIELD: Mollie!
DELAK: Order the Doctor to begin the test.
命令博士开始实验
MAXTIBLE: But I must first explain to him what he has to do.
但我必须得先跟他解释清楚要他干什么
DELAK: Go now. Obey the Daleks!
现在就去, 服从 Daleks 的命令
WATERFIELD: But your friend is vital to the plan of these Daleks.
Absolutely essential.
但你的朋友对于这些个 Daleks 的计划很关键, 绝对重要
DOCTOR: So it seems. So who could have kidnapped him?
看来是。可能是谁绑架了他？
WATERFIELD: The threats they make are not idle ones. Kennedy was murdered.
他们的警告可不说说而已的, Kennedy 就被杀死了
WATERFIELD: Without your friend, our only hope is gone...
没有你的朋友, 我们唯一的期望就没有了
WATERFIELD: unless... unless you know something.
除非。。。除非你知道些什么
WATERFIELD: You seem to be well acquainted with the creatures.
你似乎对这种生物很熟悉
DOCTOR: Everything you say, Waterfield, is true.
Waterfield, 所有你刚才说的, 都是真的
DOCTOR: If we cannot find Jamie, the Daleks
will take pleasure in killing everyone in sight,
如果我们找不到 Jamie, 这些 Daleks 会很乐意杀死这里能见到的每一个人
DOCTOR: and their greatest pleasure will be in killing me.
而让他们最高兴的事情, 是杀死我
DELAK 1: The humans have been told to begin the test.
已经通知人类开始实验
DALEK 2:Any delay will result in death.
有任何拖延都将处死
DALEK 2:There will be no delay!
不允许有拖延!